

# Md. Nahidul Islam Opu

- Mymensingh,Bangladesh +8801986980335
- opu.nahidul@gmail.com
  - nahidul-opu.github.io
  - github | in linkedin

### **ABOUT ME**

I am a student and a machine learning enthusiast. I have 2+ years of experience in game development using UnityEngine. I also have 2+ years of experience in research on machine learning. I am also interested in backend development. I am a quick learner who loves problem solving.

### SKILLS \_

- Proficient in Python, C#, C++
- Proficient in HTML, MySQL
- · Proficient in Git
- Proficient in Latex
- Proficient in Python Libraries: Pandas, Keras, Numpy etc
- OOP & Functional Programming
- Game Development (Unity Engine)

- · Machine Learning and Deep Learning
- Good understanding of data structure & algorithms
- Web Development
- Competitive programming: Codeforces (371)
- Familiar with Java, PHP, C, JavaScript, CSS, Bootstrap, Django, Android Studio

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Research Experience**

Working on Artificial Intelligence

- •Bangla handwritten character recognition using CNN. Published in MDPI Computers
- Augmented reality with machine learning
- •Covid-19 detection from chest X-ray using andorid application
- •Age and gender prediction using CNN. Published in IEEE Xplore

### **Arcade Studios**

Nov 2019 - July 2020

Intern Software Engineer

### **Arcade Studios**

July 2020 - October 2021

Junior Software Engineer (Part-time)

- Worked as a game developer using Unity Engine
- Worked on Integration of Machine Learning into Game development

### **EDUCATION** \_

# **Chittagong University of Engineering and Technology**

2017-Present

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Engineering

- Current CGPA: 3.46 (Up untill Level 3 Term II)
- · Working on Machine learning for undergraduate thesis

# Govt. Ananda Mohan College, Mymensingh

H.S.C

• GPA: 5.00

# Mymensingh Zilla School, Mymensingh

2006-2014

S.S.C

• GPA: 5.00

### PROJECTS \_\_

### **Learn to Write**

Android application to teach handwriting to kids

Using Unity3D, C#, Python and ML Libraries

### **MediCare**

An Andorid app to find doctor, hospital, ambulance with map

•Using Java, PHP, MySQL, Google Map API

### Flower Classifier

An Andorid app to classify several types of flowers

- Using Unit3D, C#, Python and ML libraries
- Deployed on Heroku using flask

#### File Locker

File vault with face recognition

Using Python and ML Libraries

### **Machine Learning Algorithms**

Pure Python implementation of several ML algorithms. Available in Github

#### **CERTIFICATIONS & TRAINING**

- Training on Machine Learning (Organized by CUET Sheikh Kamal IT Incubator)
- Applied Data Science with Python Specialization : Coursera
- Convolutional Neural Network: Coursera

### AREA OF INTEREST \_

Data Science | Software Development | Backend Development | Computer Vision

**HOBBIES** Reading Books | Watching Movies

2014-2016